what's up everybody phil blackman with
barban.com and today we are going to
talk about legendary power lifter and
bodybuilder bev francis setting new
world records in the three big lifts at
age 66 in the 64 kilogram category at a
recent powerlifting meet if you want to
learn anything about bedfrance's head
over to google type in bev francis
barban and all of the information on her
is gonna come up she is an incredible
legend in both bodybuilding and
powerlifting so let's get into it when a
legend returns to the sport expect epic
things to occur on the lifting platform
power lifter and bodybuilding legend bev
francis emerged from a 36-year
competitive powerlifting hiatus to
compete in the drug-tested meet for
world powerlifting's powerlifting
australia competing in the 64 kilogram
class in the master 65-69 division with
a body weight of 62.5 kilograms francis
cracked six powerlifting australia world
records with these results she squatted
95 kilograms or 209.4 pounds a
powerlifting australia record
she bench pressed 60 kilograms or 132.3
pounds a powerlifting australia record
she deadlifted 120 kilograms or 264.6
pounds again a powerlifting australia
world record and she totaled 275 kilos
606.3 pounds a powerlifting australia
world record france's successful squad
attempt of 90 kilograms and deadlift
attempt of 113 kilograms initially broke
the world records but her following
attempts in both lifts broke the records
again perflex magazine since 1985
francis has received rotator cuff
surgery carpal tunnel surgeries in both
wrists six arthroscopic knee surgeries
and two full knee replacements but
despite that she can still lift world
record weight in the master 65 to 69
division according to open powerlifting
france's competitive powerlifting career
included 12 sanctioned meets between
1977 and 1985 and she won all 12 of
those events competing in the 75
kilogram and 82.5 kilogram weight
classes every one of france's
competitive appearances aside from her
debut were in single ply equipped events
with her latest win in the master 65-69
division francis remains undefeated
across her powerlifting career in the 36
years between powerlifting meets francis
became a legend in the sport of
bodybuilding opening the bed france's
powerhouse gym in seattle new york also
known as the east coast mecca the 30
thousand foot facility is where multiple
mr olympia champions have trained
including four-time mr olympia jay
cutler seven-time mr olympia winner phil
heath eight-time mr olympia winner
ronnie coleman as well as celebrities
like dwayne the rock johnson francis
herself was also a world-class
bodybuilder having scored three
consecutive bronze medals at the miss
olympia competition in 1977 88 and 89
after her 10th place debut in 1986. she
improved upon that to earn a pair of
silver medal finishes on bodybuilding's
grandest stage in 1990 and 1991. now
it's unclear if francis's performance at
the powerlifting australia meet was a
one-off appearance or the beginning of a
renewed powerlifting career for the
strength sports legend but regardless
her prowess with a barbell remains and
history recognizes her as an all-time
great i'm phil bleckman for barban.com
thanks for watching
[Music]
you